Joshua Haughton

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

□ (+1) 416-998-3238 | 💌 itsjoshuahaughton@gmail.com | 🖸 JoshuaHaughton | 🛅 joshua-haughton-5ba15a22b

Tech Stack

HTML5 · CSS3 · JavaScript ES6+ · Typescript · React.js · Next.js · Jest · Mocha + Chai · Node.js · Express.js · MongoDB · PostgreSQL · GraphQL · Firebase

Summary_

A highly motivated full-stack developer with a passion for designing apps that provide an exceptional user experience. Confident in using frontend libraries and frameworks such as React and Next.js, with experience utilizing back-end technologies and eagerness to acquire new skills. An enthusiastic collaborator with the ability to understand team needs and develop ideas to meet their objectives.

Experience ____

Moonbeam Trading Company

Remote

WEB DEVELOPMENT INTERN (REACT, NEXT.JS)

Mar. 2022

- · Collaborated with others to develop a functional and responsive Next.js site from scratch for a small business.
- · Learned and applied Server-Side rendering knowledge to optimize SEO, speed up load times, and enhance user experience.
- · Led group discussions about other features to implement after completing work before deadlines

STEER.us (Talent Development Agency)

Remote

WEB DEVELOPMENT INTERN (REACT, WORDPRESS)

Mar. 2022

- · Performed bug fixes and React performance optimizations for multiple pages on the site.
- Updated CSS to provide a cleaner layout for users.

Freelance Digital Marketer

Remote

DIGITAL MARKETING SPECIALIST

Jan. 2021 - Mar. 2022

- Created and managed Facebook Ads and Email Marketing campaigns for small-mid sized E-Commerce businesses.
- · Researched customer psychology and the best ways to target customer desires/pain points for enhancing user experience.

SportingLife (Retail)

Ottawa. ON

Dec. 2020 - Dec. 2021

FOOTWEAR DEPT SPECIALIST

Positively greeted and communicated with customers and coworkers.

• Picked out specific shoes and boots best suited to each customer for their individual needs.

Projects

E-Commerce Website - Vinyl Fresh

REACT.JS, REDUX, TYPESCRIPT, FIREBASE · DEMO · GITHUB

Dec. 2021 - Apr. 2022

• A dynamic E-commerce app where users can browse and order vinyl records based on popular album covers.

Movie Finder/Saver - Watchlist

REACT.JS, NODE.JS, EXPRESS.JS, MONGODB, TMDBAPI · DEMO · GITHUB

Dec. 2021 - Mar. 2022

· A media searching app, allowing users to find and save movies and tv shows to their watchlist, as well as rate them and check them off their list.

Crypto Tracker

REACT.JS, NEXT.JS, REDUX, COINGECKO API, FIREBASE · DEMO · GITHUB

Apr. 2022 - May. 2022

· A Next.js app where users can find detailed information and chart data on their favourite Cryptocurrencies.

LinkedIn Remake

REACT.JS, REDUX, TYPESCRIPT, FIREBASE · DEMO · GITHUB

Mar. 2022 - Apr. 2022

• A LinkedIn remake built to learn more about Redux and Typescript. Users can create an account, make posts, and view posts other users make in real-time

Education

Web Development Diploma Oct. 2021 - Jan. 2022

• An Intensive 12-week Bootcamp which gave me a deep understanding of front-end/back-end languages, frameworks and programming concepts through many solo and collaborative projects.

Carleton University Ottawa, ON

B.A. IN PSYCHOLOGY (HALF-COMPLETE)

Sep. 2019 - Sep. 2021

• Completed 2 years towards degree; learned the customer psychology skills necessary to fully transition into digital marketing.